<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[David Perel's Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://dperel.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dperel.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-25T00:15:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://dperel.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Perel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bindings in Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://dperel.github.io/blog/2015/06/24/bindings-in-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-24T22:13:35-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dperel.github.io/blog/2015/06/24/bindings-in-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Do you see the binding? </strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.artinthepicture.com/artists/Jan_van_Eyck/arnolfini.jpeg"></p>

<h3> What is a binding? </h3>


<p>When using Embedded Ruby, Ruby programmers become aware of the importance of binding. In order to use ERB&rsquo;s templating tool to generate HTML (or other language) documents using Ruby, a binding is required to take a snapshot of the current code and pass it to be executed. Let&rsquo;s use this code snippet where we assume there is a Movie class with an array of information-laden movie objects made accessible by calling Movie.all:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'> <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">generate_movie_webpages</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">html</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">File</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">read</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;lib/templates/movie.html.erb&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class="n">template</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">ERB</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">new</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">html</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c1">#From our movie.html.erb file we generate a new ERB template </span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="vi">@movies</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">Movie</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">all</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="vi">@movies</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">each</span> <span class="k">do</span> <span class="o">|</span><span class="n">movie</span><span class="o">|</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="vi">@movie</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">movie</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">result</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">template</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">result</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">binding</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="no">File</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">write</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;_site/movies/</span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">movie</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">result</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c1">#For each movie object in our list, we generate a page based</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c1">#on the template and store it at a unique address.</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Notice where binding came in there? It was in the loop, taking a snapshot of the code as it stood and passing it to the ERB execution method, template#result(). We&rsquo;ve seen some of what it can do. But why do we have to use this, and where does it get its power from?</p>

<h3> Where does binding come from? </h3>


<p>To start our inquiry into its roots, here are some short definitions of binding:</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;It squishes the universe into one singular object that I can then pass around.&rdquo;</em> - Avi Flombaum, Rubyista Extraordinaire</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Logic of a quantifier to be applied to a given variable so that the variable falls within its scope.
For example, in an expression of the form. Example: For every x, if x is a dog, x is an animal,’ the universal quantifier is binding the variable x.&rdquo; </em> - Oxford English Dictionary</p>

<p>This is a good start. It seems that binding grabs the universe of code as it is at that line of processing, packs it in a pill, and allows your template to ingest it for execution. <strong>But where exactly does binding come from? What kind of method or object is it? </strong>To help us out, I&rsquo;ve reached into the Ruby Documentation.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Objects of class Binding encapsulate the execution context at some particular place in the code and retain this context for future use. The variables, methods, value of self, and possibly an iterator block that can be accessed in this context are all retained. Binding objects can be created using Kernel#binding.&rdquo; - Ruby-doc.org</p>

<p>Those first and last lines answer our question: <strong>Binding is a class that produces instances, and it belongs to Kernel. </strong> Kernel! The all important nugget at the center of our Ruby popcorn. Binding even has several public instance methods that allow you to examine what it contains. Binding.local_variables and Binding.local_variable_defined? are useful.</p>

<h3> Bringing it all together:</h3>


<p>Binding&rsquo;s relation to Kernel explains its ability to pack variables, methods, the value of self, and possibly an iterator block into a single word. Binding gives the Pry gem its power, and it enables ERB templates to make the most of your Ruby code when generating code in other langauages. <strong>Binding is an open lens into a universe of code. Binding is the world seen through a water droplet. Binding is encapsulation. <strong></p>

<p><strong> Do you see the binding now? </strong></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.oneonta.edu/faculty/farberas/arth/Images/ARTH_214images/van_eyck/arnolfini/center.jpg"></p>

<p><em>
Painting: Jan Van Eyck&rsquo;s Portrait of Giovanni Arnolfini and his Bride, Flemish, 1434</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Bootcamps and the Changing Face of Tech]]></title>
    <link href="http://dperel.github.io/blog/2015/06/11/code-bootcamps-and-the-changing-face-of-tech/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-11T00:03:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dperel.github.io/blog/2015/06/11/code-bootcamps-and-the-changing-face-of-tech</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Steve Jobs once stated that the Mac represented the intersection between technology and the liberal arts. Code schools are mirroring this evolution in the nature of technology by training web and app developers from liberal arts backgrounds.</p>

<p>16,000 code school graduates are expected to enter the workforce this year, which is a 138% increase from last year. At this rate, code school graduates from diverse backgrounds will cause a transformation of the tech industry. Here’s how.</p>

<p>Technology is only as good as what it can do, and the people who make it decide what it can do. At Flatiron School, the student body is evenly split between women and men. Most of us studied liberal arts, and many of us have worked as teachers, as designers, and as consultants. We can tell that we are a different breed from the current generation of programmers because we constantly find errors in sentence clarity and spelling in programming resources on the internet. We find gaps in those websites' instructions that obscure the point of certain exercises. To many of us, it is apparent that most programmers out there don’t have a background that lets them communicate their craft easily to non-programmers. By learning to code and pushing through those difficulties, we’re chinking away at a long-standing wall between science and humanities.</p>

<p>Steve Jobs’ Mac already bridged the user end of the divide between liberal arts and science. Flatiron School and programs like it (but not == to it) are bridging the divide on the designer end. What does this mean for the future of programming, which is the heart of the technology industry?</p>

<p>A friend of mine who studied at Flatiron School in an earlier cohort put her experience in the following way. Her university degree allowed her to follow her interests in the humanities, but it didn’t provide her with hard skills to translate her passion into her career. This is where Flatiron came in. Flatiron School gives a new group of people, with knowledge and interests uncommon among today’s web and app developers, a way to make something of their own. If the Mac provided the platform for the intersection of liberal arts and technology, Flatiron School and programs like it are graduating the people who will build upon that platform.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
